Kevin Adrian Pillay

kevin@kevinadrian.dev +27786053498 https://www.kevinadrian.dev

♥ KwaZulu-Natal

PROFILE

I'm a System Administrator and Security Professional with a history of working in multiple industries. I'm experienced in IT management, server management, system administration, and information security. I have a passion for technology and work on multiple projects to keep up with the ever-changing industry.

References and certifications available on request.

EDUCATION

IT Academy, Cyber Security Specialist 2021 - 2022University of South Africa (UNISA), Information Technology 2010 - 2011Boston City Campus, Information Technology 2009 - 2010 Isandlwana Technical High School, High School Diploma 2003 - 2008

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT System Administrator, Novus Holdings Ltd (ITB Plastics)

2015 - present Isithebe, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

- Install and upgrade computer components and software, manage virtual servers, and integrate automation.
- Troubleshoot hardware/software errors by running diagnostics, documenting and prioritizing problems.
- Provide documentation and technical specifications.
- Maintain backups and implement data protection and fail-over procedures.
- Run desktop and help-desk support, ensuring desktop applications/workstation problems are resolved with limited disruptions.
- Server administration tasks, permissions, policies, print services, event log errors, and resource monitoring.
- Setup company laptops, desktops, barcode scanners, printers, switches, DECT/IP phones, smartphones, software deployment, security updates, and patches.
- LANs, WANs, Internet, and intranet systems.
- Maintain network, system security and WSUS deployment
- · Troubleshoot technical issues relating to factory machinery.
- Troubleshoot and resolve issues reported by end-users.
- Installing, configuring, and maintaining Microsoft Server 2012, 2016 and 2019.
- Active Directory account/group setup and maintaining integrity of user database.
- Monitoring and maintaining network servers such as file servers, VPN/firewalls, and intrusion detection systems on virtual servers using VMware (vSphere Client).
- Monitoring and maintaining Symantec Endpoint Protection.
- Microsoft Exchange and O365 support.
- Interact with departments to assist in troubleshooting, providing technical support.
- · Perform routine audits of the systems/backups.
- Oversee Time and Attendance and bio-metric devices.
- Support for ERP software (Syspro) to employees.
- Support for a custom software.
- SQL database management and writing of SQL queries to automate procedures.
- Oversee CCTV/surveillance setup and maintenance.
- PABX management and maintenance.
- · Oversee information security related tasks.

Network Technician, Mactron Technology

• Maintained and upgraded client networks, routers, switches, and running of network cabling.

2013 – 2015 Eshowe, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

- Diagnosed computer issues and installed software on various equipment.
- Scheduled maintenance on client computers.
- Day to day technical support and customer service.
- Assisted with servers, LAN/WAN, network related issues, security audits.
- Deployed Trend Micro and ESET.
- Installed and maintained IT infrastructure for local schools and companies.
- Help-desk support and escalation of tickets.

IT Technician, Genmac Engineering and Construction CC

2011 - 2012

 Assisted with installation, configuration, and support of system hardware and software in the company.

• Installed and maintained Windows Server 2012, mainly email and file servers.

Richards Bay, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

- Day to day systems support to employees.
- Troubleshooting remote issues with offsite sales representatives.
- · Network security and backup procedures.
- · Assisted with general engineering operations.
- Basic AutoCAD.

Junior Technician, S and N Projects

2010 - 2011

• Monitored day to day functions of company computers/laptops.

Richards Bay, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

- Daily and monthly backups using Veaam.
- LAN and WLAN connectivity inside the company.
- SQL database management and network security.
- Remote assistance to offsite employees.
- · Active Directory user and group management.
- CCTV maintenance.

2009 – 2010

Richards Bay, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

Trainee, Boston City Campus & Business College

Help-desk support services to the trainer at campus.

- Support for applications such as Microsoft Office and other basic software.
- Assisted with general office duties such as network cabling, configuring DNS, installing Windows.
- Configured and shared printers.
- Assisted with day to day maintenance on computers used in campus by students.
- Security reports to the technical trainer.

SKILLS

 $\textbf{SQL Server} \ (Microsoft \ SQL, \ MySQL) \ \mid \ \textbf{System Administration} \ (Microsoft, Linux) \ \mid \ \textbf{Exchange} \ (Office \ O365)$

Scripting (Python, Bash, PowerShell) | Virtualization (VMware vSphere, Hyper-V, Proxmox, ESXi)

Network Security (Pentesting, Nmap, Metasploit) | Windows Server (AD, RDS, WSUS)

IT Management (Policies, SDLC) | Cloud Computing (Azure, Google Cloud)

E CERTIFICATES

CS₅

CompTIA A+ CompTIA N+

Excel on Steroids Acceys PeopleWare T&A

Adobe Dreamweaver Google IT Support Professional Certificate

IT Security

2/3

PROJECTS

Static Website

A static security blog/personal website that is hosted through GitHub Pages and Netlify.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

https://www.kevinadrian.dev/ 🛭

Blazor HelpDesk

An open source helpdesk web application written using Blazor Server Side.

HTML, C#, Blazor

https://github.com/kevinadrianpl/helpdesk/ ☑



W VOLUNTEERING

Hosted Game Server, Owner

2018 - present

Own and manage a small non-profit, publicly accessible LAMP gaming server, includes monitoring, maintenance, troubleshooting, and basic security.

South African Red Cross Society (SARCS), Trainee

August 2008

Attended prescribed courses of lectures and demonstrations in 'Save a life', including CPR training and basic first aid.